

Kevin Lacroix

I am looking for the opportunity to progress my professional career as a front-end developer in Wellington. With four years of corporate and agency experience, I have worked on a variety of large and small projects that kept me challenged and working with the latest techniques and technologies. Passionate about combining the art of design with the art of programming, I enjoy translating web designs into code.

WORK HISTORY

05/2015 - 09/2017

FRONT-END DEVELOPER - NEOLYNK - Paris (France)

Neolynk is an IT services company including 60 to 80 employees.

I had the opportunity to work on two heavy traffic websites: one for a media group and the other for a pharmaceutical company. I also worked for two notorious companies in the luxury sector where pixel-perfect layouts and great performance are a requirement. Below are the **5 assignments** I worked on:

03/2017 - 09/2017

1) FRANCETV SPORT

With 5 national television channels, 24 regional branches, 9 ultramarine antennas and a full range of digital services, France Télévisions is the leading French public service audiovisual group. This project is a complete redisign of the Sport platform. I arrived at the very begining of the project. There was 4 Back-end developpers and I was the only one in charge of the Front-end.

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- Successfully automated a workflow on the front-end for maximum performance
- HTML/CSS integration following atomic design principles
- + Use of TWIG Templating Engine on Symfony3 framework
- + Improved skills in SEO (HTML5 standards, AMP, Charbeat, JSONLD, microdata...)
- + Improved skills in Vanilla JS, ES6 (Babel) and Ajax
- + Worked in Agile / Scrum environments, used Jira
- Use of Drupal 8 Back Office
- + Use of Jenkins

Technical stack: Gulp, jQuery, Sass, Git, Bitbucket

01/2016 - 02/2017

2) UNIVADIS

Within Ultra Noir web agency, I was working on the Univadis website, a heavy traffic website, for its client Aptus Health, pharmaceutical company.

The website is a platform dedicated to doctors from different trades. It allows them to access to a large base of content divided in 3 sections: News, Reference (mini-app), Education (interactive quizz).

There was 8 Back-end developpers and we were 2 Front-end developpers. When I arrived, the project had already started since one year.

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- + Redesign of the old platform with specificities for each countries
- Design were done on Sketch and available on Zeplin.
- Work in a Symfony2 environment
- + Creation of CSS components using BEM and OOCSS methodology
- + Use of TWIG Templating Engine in a Symfony2 environment
- + Job interviewing to assess new candidates skills

With the brain of the product in Paris, and the backend developpers in the south of France, the communication between the different parties of the team collaboration with an Agile methodologies impliqua many exchnage with calls and webcam.

Technical stack: Gulp, jQuery, Sass, Git, Bitbucket

01/2016 - 02/2016

3) CHANEL

Chanel is a high fashion house that specializes in haute couture and ready-to-wear clothes, luxury goods and fashion accessories. For this short project, I implemented some widgets on a one-page that needed to be independent. The client wanted to be able to add them or remove them from a Back Office. https://www.chanel.com/fr_-FR/parfums-beaute/maquillage/c/chanel-beauty-talks.html

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- + Successfully automated a workflow on the front-end for maximum performance
- + HTML/CSS integration following atomic design principles

Technical stack: Grunt, jQuery, Sass, Git

10/2015 - 12/2015

4) CHAUMET

Chaumet is a parisian jeweller since 1780. It sells high jewellery and watches in many boutiques in the world main capital cities.

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- + Redesign of the existing Chaumet website.
- Responsive integration in HTML5 / CSS3
- + Theming on Drupal 7

Technical stack: jQuery, Sass, Git, Vagrant

07/2015 - 09/2015

5) TRACEONE:

The project is an application allowing manufacturers, retailer and providers to have a better visibility on the products supply chains. The Backend is in .Net and the front-end in AngularJS. Both sides communicate via a REST API.

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- Worked in .NET environment (Visual Studio, TFS)
- + CSS refactoring to create independent components for each module, using DoCSSa methodology (inspired
- + of BEM methodology). Components are created via Sass mixins.
- + Worked in Agile / Scrum environments, used Jira
- Use of Phabricator as a code review tool
- + Basic use of AngularJS to fetch data on the REST API via GET calls
- + Basic understanding of Browserify, Parcelify

Technical stack: Gulp, jQuery, Sass, Git, Bitbucket

10/2014 - 03/2015

FRONT-END DEVELOPER - Les Evadés - Montreal (Canada)

Les Evadés is an Advertising agency including 20 to 30 employees. We were 2 developpers to cover the need on the web activity. My responsabilities mainly were about maintaining or integrating small evolutions on client websites. I was also integrating landing pages for advertising campaigns.

The biggest challenge was to learn and use AngularJS on the redesign of the agency website.

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- + Use of Sass and Stylus preprocessors
- + Use of HTML5 Microdata
- Workflow automation with Gulp / Use of Yeoman gulp-angular
- Basic use of Angular: creation of directives and use of Angular core directives, use of Angular PictureFill
- Interactive animation using SVG, jQuery and CSS3
- Development of a jQuery slider plugin that would always fit to the height of the window and remain responsive
- + Use of Google Map, YouTube and Vimeo API

Technical stack: Sass/Stylus, Yeoman, Bower, NPM, git, Bitbucket

FRONT-END DEVELOPER - HOFFMAN AGENCY - Montreal (Canada)

Hoffman Agency is a digital agency of about 20 employees is specialized in digital development. I had the opportunity to work most of the time on new projects for new clients of the agency.

The Backend that was used was usually Wordpress for small projects and Laravel for bigger projects. Also i had to use Codelgniter for the evolution of an old project.

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- + HTML5 / CSS3 responsive integration
- + Use Stylus preprocessors and Stylus libraries (Nibs, Axis, Jeet, Rupture)
- + Front-end interactivity and animation with jQuery
- + Code versionning with Git
- + Theme creation with Wordpress
- Templating on Laravel framework
- + Assets and build optimization with Grunt
- Use of Google Map, YouTube and Facebook API
- Wordpress: use of the starter theme Underscore. Use of the following plugins: Custom Post Type, Advanced
 Custom Field, Wordpress BulletProof Security. Management of the client permissions.
- Use of polyfills for IE8 compatibility.
- + Project management with Trello

Technical stack: Sass/Stylus, Yeoman, Bower, NPM, git, Bitbucket

09/2013 - 02/2014

FRONT-END DEVELOPER - ACOLYTE COMMUNICATION- Trois-Rivières (Canada)

Acolyte Communication is a web agency of about 25 - 30 employees. I had the opportunity to work mostly on new projects for new clients of the agency.

I also did a little support for existing websites.

The Backend was a home made CMS for all projects.

TASKS AND DUTIES:

- + HTML5 / CSS3 responsive integration
- + Use of Less preprocesseur
- + Use of Bootstrap UX framework
- + Use of SVG sprites
- + Front-end interactivity and animation with jQuery
- + Use of Polyfills for IE8 support
- Use of jQuery, jQuery plugins, Bootstrap plugins for front-end interactivity
- + W3C standards
- + Project management with Basecamp

2010 - 2012

TECHNICAL SALES REPRESENTATIVE - EDICAD - Cahors (France)

Technical and business skills from my education in France led me a sales representative job position. I had the responsability to develop the business in the west of France, to enlarge the client base and to propose software updates to existing clients. The product was Conception assisted by Computer Software dedicated to people working in the building industry such as architects...

After being a sales representative in France, I went to Canada (Québec) in 2012, to undertake a new career in web development.

EDUCATION

09/2012 - 09/2013

AEC IN WEB DEVELOPMENT - CEGEP OF TROIS-RIVIÈRES - Trois-Rivières (Canada)

STUDY OF THE FOLLOWING TOPICS:

- + Web design
- + HTML / CSS
- Javascript
- + PHP
- + Wordpress
- + SEO
- + E-Commerce

BACHELOR IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING - University of Cergy-Pontoise (France)

- Specialization in Business during my last year
- + One year spent in Huddersfield, UK

AREA OF INTEREST

Beside my enthusiasm about the Web and emerging technologies the Web, I like sport, hiking, travelling, photography, board games, cinema and exhibitions.

- + Sport
- + Hiking
- + Travelling
- + Photography
- + Board games
- + Cinema
- + Exhibitions

REFEREES

Beside my enthusiasm about the Web and emerging technologies the Web, I like sport, hiking, travelling, photography, board games, cinema and exhibitions.

- + Sport
- + Hiking
- + Travelling
- + Photography
- + Board games
- + Cinema
- + Exhibitions